A Guide to the Fairfax County Emergency Services Patch Collection, c.1940-c.2000
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Fairfax County Emergency Services Patch Collection, c.1940-c.2000
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 09-23
0.25 linear feet
The Fairfax County Emergency Services Patch Collection consists of 0.25 linear feet and spans the years c.1940 - c.2000.
Conley, Brian A. (1964- )
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection assembled by former Virginia Room librarian and historian Brian A. Conley. Gifted July 2019.
Historical and Biographical Information
The earliest documentation of Fairfax County police officers using patches dates to 1940. When the Fairfax County Police Department became a stand-alone agency on July 1, 1940, officers began wearing a triangle-shaped patch on their outer jackets. By the mid-1940s, officers started wearing this patch on their uniform shirts. The police department subsequently issued a variety of patches over the years including unit produced patches. The present patch worn by police officers dates to 1963 of which several iterations have been issued over the years. The Fairfax County Fire & Rescue Department, Fairfax County Park Authority, Sheriff’s Office, City of Fairfax, Town of Herndon, and Town of Vienna have also issued patches for their public safety officers throughout their history.
Scope and Content
The Fairfax County Emergency Services Patch Collection consists of 0.25 linear feet, spans the years c.1940 - c.2000 and features various patches used by the Fairfax County Police Department, Fairfax County Fire & Rescue Department, Fairfax County Sheriff’s Office, City of Fairfax Police Department, Town of Herndon Police Department, Town of Vienna Police Department, Fairfax County Park Authority, and George Mason University Campus Police.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax (Va.). Police Department; Fairfax County (Va.). Fire and Rescue Department.; Fairfax County (Va.). Police Department; Fire departments -- Virginia -- Fairfax County; Herndon (Va.). Department of Police; Police -- Virginia -- Fairfax; Police -- Virginia -- Fairfax County; Police -- Virginia -- Herndon; Police -- Virginia -- Vienna; Vienna (Va.). Police Department
Container List
- Patch, "Fairfax Volunteer Fire Dept.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax Volunteer Fire Dept.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax Town Police Va." (Marr Monument and cannon logo), Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax Police Va." (Marr Monument and cannon logo), c. 1960s (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax Police Va." (Marr Monument and cannon logo), c. 1960s (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax City Police Va." (Marr Monument and cannon logo), Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "City of Fairfax Virginia Police", c. 1980s (Box 1)
- Patch, "Annandale Vol. Fire Dept. Fairfax County Va." (Ossian Hall logo), Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax City Police Virginia" (Courthouse and cannon logo), c. 1960s (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax City Police Virginia" (Courthouse and cannon logo), c. 1960s (Box 1)
- Patch, "City of Fairfax, Virginia Fire and Rescue Services", 1978 (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax County Police Va." (triangle patch), c. 1940 (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va." (Mount Vernon logo), c. 1953-1963 (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va." (Mount Vernon logo), c. 1953-1963 (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Virginia" (black), c. 1988-2000 (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Virginia", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Virginia", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Special Police Fairfax County", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax County Public Safety Communications", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Animal Control Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Crossing Guard Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Parking Enforcement Fairfax County Virginia", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Auxiliary Police Fairfax County Virginia", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Virginia", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Park Police Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax County Park Ranger", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax County Park Authority", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Fairfax Sheriffs Office", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Sheriff's Dept. Fairfax County Va.", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Herndon Town Police", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Herndon Police" (Herndon Depot logo), Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "George Mason University Campus Police", Undated (Box 1)
- Patch, "Police Vienna", Undated (Box 1)